Chapter 1

Ron dashed along the sandy track, trying to overtake his speedy friend Josh. An idea formed in his mind, and the boy transformed into a cheetah. He overtook Josh and crossed the finish line first. He sat there, very tired.

“Cheating! Cheating!” Josh panted as he crossed the line. The cheetah shrugged and changed back into Ron.

The four friends May, Carra, Ron and Josh were in Imagneus, a planet far from Earth. The four had been normal Earthlings until they met Iris, a Ronen, and joined her race as Ronens, and had all travelled to Imagneus. It was tough though, as their parents agreed to send them with only one parent for each. The Ronens were preparing for a war in Imagneus against an evil Streo called Grinlaut. They won over Grinlaut, and had spent the past two months rebuilding their homeland.

“That is not cheating,” Avaron, the leader and Iris’ father, said.

“How come?” Josh asked, surprised.

“It is part of Ronen to transform. That trait will, of course, be allowed in every competition.”

“But it didn’t say so in the banner!” Josh protested.

“That goes without saying,” Avaron smiled.

The four friends had been transformed into Ronens, and the Clan had accepted them readily.

Ron was ecstatic. He punched Josh, who wasn’t ready to accept that he had lost a running race for the first time ever in his life.

Ron grinned and looked up. Satiro, one of the three moons on Imagneus, was out. Quirodon was partly visible, half hidden by clouds. The other came and went as it pleased. There was no telling that Faztex would rise. Faztex was the auspicious blue moon, Quirodon was the lucky silver moon and Satiro was the beautiful red moon. Each moon had its own night- Dusk of Satiro, Dawn of Quirodon, and the Night of Faztex.

Josh sighed wearily and trudged past other celebrating Ronens to his makeshift bed.

The Ronens always held ceremonies, functions and parties only on the nights when Faztex rose. They did so because it was said that the Ronens rose to glory from ashes on the Night of Faztex. Ivy and Leif, Iris’ siblings had told the four the story-

“The leader then was Kortis. He was selected as the leader, and everyone had high hopes; he was young, strong and had a lot of ambition. He strengthened the clan and was a just and kind leader. He was the one who started the tradition of worshipping the moons. He took back the lands that had been stolen from them. One night, he decided to defeat the tyrant king of Imagneus, and he led the Ronens along with other clans to battle on the Night of Faztex. We won, and Kortis himself was chosen as the king of Imagneus. Now the tradition of kings is gone, but still we celebrate the Night of Faztex.”

Ron reached the bedroom first, and fell on his bed happily. The camp was not yet fully restored, and everyone had to make-do with what they had. Pal, Ron’s bond, climbed onto Ron’s bed and squashed him under his weight. Ron shoved the dog off, and Pal whimpered. Josh made his grand entry and slumped on his bed. Carra and May came in, called out a ‘good night’ and the four were sleeping by the time their parents came in.

They woke up to Victoria’s morning alarm. Tabitha, Carra’s bond, a cat, mewed a greeting and strolled out, with Carra beside her, with Ron and Pal following. May waved to them from where she and her bond were helping May’s mother to cook. Josh was left in his bed, sleeping.

The friends joined Iris and her sisters at the table, where the Ronens were serving breakfast. Ruben, a magnificent hawk, also Iris’ bond, flew over and sat down beside them.

“Where is Josh?” Ivy asked.

“Snoring,” Tabitha mewed, yawning.

“She asked ‘where is he’, not ‘what’s he doing’,” Ron pointed out.

“He’s snoring in Jupiter. Happy?” Tabitha twitched her tail, irritated.

When they were washing the plates after breakfast, Josh dashed over. “What’d I miss?” He panted.

“Most important meal of the day,” May said. “There’s some left I think. Go eat quickly.” He raced off, leaving clouds of dust trailing behind him.

The four met later on, with Iris, and decided to go for a walk. No sooner had they set foot out of the camp, that they heard Romial, the deputy, call May and Ron. The two quickly muttered their farewell and ran away with their bonds.

Iris, Carra and Josh strolled around the camp, wondering what to do, when suddenly, a horrifying screech caused them to look up. A three-legged beast with a monstrous face and short wings was hovering in the air, clutching a young boy, who was wailing desperately. He had white feathery wings, which were cruelly tied up. The creature let go of the boy, and he fell straight amidst the massing Ronens.

The plan would work perfectly. The Shadow of Death watched the events unfold on his magical waterfall with unpleasant happiness. The shimmering water on the waterfall showed his trusted captain, Gillsor, dropping the winged boy into the Ronen Clan. He let out an evil chuckle. He watched with avid interest as an eagle (or was it a hawk?) grab the boy and lay him gently on the ground. The scarred face of the Shadow twisted into a hideous smile. His animal-like yellow eyes glittered hungrily, desiring a power only the Ronens could hand him.

The winged boy was waking up. He groaned, then bolted up straight, fully alert. Two score Ronens stood watching him suspiciously. Three Ronens were standing near his bed. One was gazing at him curiously, inspecting his hand, which was mysteriously glowing faintly. The boy pulled his hand away. The other two were checking a list and muttering something.

“Herbulen, step aside,” a tall man strode forward, gently shoving the doctor aside. “What’s your name?” He asked.

“Fivlon,” the boy said. “Harra boschon,” the boy said. He muttered something else inaudible, and his eyes welled up with tears. He furled and unfurled his wings, and then let it lay limp at his sides.

The tall man looked at him, and then said, “Leave him for now. Apparently, he doesn’t know English.”

He posted two guards outside the room, and left with the others. The boy looked at the closed door, and smiled cunningly. How easy it was to fool them! Of course he knew the language! Why, hadn’t he been the one to endure years of suffering by following them to Earth and noting their every move? No time to waste, he thought, and pulled out a small disk from his wings. His wings were the latest edition which came with extra large storage.

There were a number of dials on the disk. He pressed them in a pattern, and it started turning slowly. It clicked once, twice, and then a beam of light fell on it. It turned faster and faster, enlarging as it spun, until it was the size of a basket. Then it stopped, and the light flickered and was gone. The disk glowed with the same light his hand had glowed with. The Shadow of Death’s face appeared, cruel and menacing as usual. The Shadow smiled, and the boy knew the Death Lord was pleased with him.

Chapter 4

They all stared, dumbfounded, as the hazy shape of the black bird vanished into the night. The moon glowed dully as they trudged the last few kilometres to the hotel.

They sat outside, on a bench. Amy sighed wearily.

“What do we do now? The car’s wrecked,” Josh said unhappily.

“I don’t know, kids.” Amy sighed again.

“Where exactly did Avaron say the lotus was?” Zevyn asked.

“He said it was in a dangerous forest, right? In an underground cave or something.” Iris said.

“Where do you think that would be?” May asked.

“I know some caves around Switzerland,” Josh said.

“I don’t think it’s there,” Snowflake said quietly.

“Maybe....umm... how about in Mexico?”

“Doubt it.”

“Africa?”

“Maybe.”

“We could try out in some historical site, don’t you think?” Iris asked.

“Yeah. Which is the most historical place, do you know, Mrs. Anderson?” Ron asked Amy.

“India!” Ruben suddenly cried out.

“What?” Iris asked her bond, confused.

Ruben stared blankly at Iris, even more dazed than the girl. “What did I just say?” he asked, blinking.

“You just said ‘India’,” Pal explained.

“I have never even heard of it. It just kind of flashed in my mind.”

“Like someone mind-messaged you?” Josh asked, laughing.

Ruben nodded. “Seriously? I was joking!” Josh cried.

“India does have a good history. It was really rich in culture,” Carra’s mother said.

“Maybe we could try there.” Pal suggested.

“Yeah, only thing is how can you get there?” Tabitha asked.

“I have a good friend in the airlines. I could ask her to give us a lift.” Amy said, fishing out her mobile phone from her purse.

Lyke and Zevyn had been watching this exchange with interest.

“Where is India?”Lyke asked. “India is across the ocean, in the southern part of Asia,” Josh replied promptly. Josh always had a good memory when it came to Geography.

Carra’s mother dialled her friend. They spoke for a few moments, and then Amy cut the call.

“She said she’ll be delighted to have us,” Amy said with a sparkle in her eyes.

Very soon, they were at a private landing site, waiting with their luggage, which was pretty much stuff which they had just bought.

A blue and white plane gracefully landed in front of them. The door opened and a young woman popped out. She waved to them. She was tan and had a head of brown curls. Amy embraced her, and told her not to freak out if the animals talk. But she adjusted quickly, and didn’t lose her nerve for a second.

“Well, get in! What are you waiting for?” the young woman called, grinning. The children and animals climbed aboard and sat comfortably. There was enough space in the back for Ruben to sit at ease, without his wings getting cramped.

The plane rolled down the runway, with Jemma, Amy’s friend, called out instructions in the headset.

“Please fasten your seat belts! We are about to take off!” she called cheerfully.

Zevyn stared at the mechanism. She listened carefully as Josh and Carra explained how the plane works. Lykenzar gazed out the window, lost in his own thoughts. The animals played a game which they just invented. May, Ron and Iris joined them. Amy called Ron’s father and Josh’s mother to inform them that they were going to India. She filled the other two parents about everything that happened.

“Where are we going exactly, Jemma?” May asked.

“Delhi, the capital of India,” the pilot called back.

May nodded and focused her attention back on the game.

“I hope they got the message,” Avaron fretted.

“They would have, don’t worry.” His wife sat down next to him.

“So, they know where to go, don’t they?” Ivy asked. She was with her family, pacing back and forth restlessly. Avaron nodded.

“Sit down, Ivy. They are fine, as you can see for yourself,” Leif said. Ivy nodded absently and sat down heavily.

Minkin tore his gaze from his crystals. He and Jasper had set it up, the crystals forming a border to a pool of water. He blessed it, and a vivid scene of all of the children formed in the water.

Avaron had sent a mind message to them, and hopefully, he thought, one of them would have received it and relayed it to the others. But, something the pilot said was wrong. He couldn’t find out what it was. He frowned, gazing at the crystals harder.

“What is it? What is wrong?” Raptor, Avaron’s wife’s bond, asked.

“That Jemma. She said something. I cannot put my finger on it.” He bit his lip. After a moment of intense thinking, he sighed.

“You will get to know, don’t worry,” Victoria said. “And when you do, it will not be too late for you to change their course.”

Chapter 6

“That was a horrible flight!” Lyke groaned.

“Totally agree,” Josh said. They had arrived in the city of Bangalore, and were in a taxi cab to civilization.

They arrived soon, and the greedy taxi driver demanded his money. Amy quickly gave him the taxi fare and climbed off. The taxi sped away into the distance, leaving a gust of wind and dust swirling around them.

Ron coughed. “What a (cough) meano!” he exclaimed, waving the dust away from him with his hand.

“Come on, we’re wasting time!” May urged, pulling their luggage and Snowflake’s cage behind her. The flight and police authorities had insisted on keeping the rabbit, Pete, Ruben and Tabitha in a cage and Pal on a leash at all times. But as soon as they arrived, Iris let Ruben free. He immediately took to his blue haven.

“Where do we go now?” Ron asked.

“Let’s go get a hotel first. Then we’ll see about the lotus,” Amy insisted.

“Where’s a hotel?” Ron demanded.

“We can ask that driver of that weird thing, maybe,” Carra suggested, looking pointedly at a man standing beside an auto rickshaw.

“Hmm.”

The group crossed the road and stood in front of the driver. He looked up from the newspaper he was reading.

“Can you please tell us the way to the nearest hotel where we can stay?” Amy asked politely.

The auto driver said something incomprehensible to the group.

“Excuse me?”

Suddenly, Zevyn said something to the auto driver in another language and he replied. Everybody stared at her except Lykenzar, who puffed out his chest with pride.

“She has the gift of tongues,” he said importantly.

“Why didn’t you use it before?” May asked curiously.

“Well, I don’t know it all the time. When I need it, it just flashes and I know the language by-heart.”

“What did he say?” Iris asked.

“We have to go a bit down this road, take the right next to a medical shop, and on the left side, one house before the road ends, is the hotel,” she said.

They followed her instructions and came to a hotel. Carra’s mother eyed it critically. Then she shrugged and led the way in.

Zevyn quickly spoke with the manager, and handed over a room key to Amy. But before they could go, the manager said something else. Zevyn clarified it, and turned to her friends.

“Sorry, guys,” she held her hands up apologetically. “No animals allowed here.”

Carra groaned.

“Then where do we keep them?” Iris demanded.

The manager walked up to them. Speaking in broken English, he said that they could leave the animals in the pet shop opposite the hotel.

Amy thanked him, and hustled the group out of the hotel. The children followed grudgingly; none of them were happy at the thought of being separated from their bonds.

They made their farewells short, and returned to the hotel quickly.

The next morning, the group checked out, and quickly collected the animals. They purchased a map from a local store and stood on the side of the narrow street to study it.

“Hmm. We’re... here, I think,” Carra’s mother mused.

“Maybe we should check out a library to see the most historical places here,” Lyke suggested. Pal grunted softly in agreement. As if his barks had summoned them, two stray dogs shot out of their places from under a car and stood menacingly in front of Pal, snarling. Pal stared back, confused.

“We’d better go,” Zevyn said uncertainly. Amy nodded, and the group set off swiftly, Ron glancing back now and then to see if the dogs were still pursuing his bond. Thankfully, they left them when they rounded the corner of the street. Lyke and Zevyn glanced at each other in puzzlement.

“Let’s keep moving,” Iris said with a worried glance behind her back.

Carra’s mother nodded, and led the group away. They paused briefly to check the map again, and made their way to the nearest library.

They left Lykenzar, Ron and Iris outside with the animals. Once inside, they asked the librarian for historical books. She showed them and walked back to her desk, smiling at them.

The group rooted out every possible book which had a possibility of giving them their answer. After a strenuous hour of searching, May finally triumphantly shouted out, “I’ve got it!”

The others immediately bunched around her. “See?” she said pointing out the page. “It’s right there. Hampi,” she said. The others nodded. Zevyn took the book from May and read it out loud.

Amy nodded when she finished. “You’re right. We should go there as soon as possible.”

Suddenly, her phone rang. She picked it up, and talked quickly. When she cut the call, she looked very excited.

“What is it?” Carra asked her mother.

“Ron’s dad just called. He’s here it seems. He left Jessica in Josh’s house. He has a very close friend in Bangalore, and we can stay there for the night, and tomorrow, we can all leave for Hampi.”

They placed all the books back as soon as they could, and thanking the librarian, they shuffled out. They told the others the news.

“Cool!” Ron said, apparently amazed at how fast news travelled. Lykenzar nodded approvingly, while Iris resorted to talking excitedly to Ruben.

Ron’s dad picked them up from a hotel. As they drove, they filled him in on other details.

The journey to the neighbourhood of Ron’s dad’s friend was one hour. The car was an eight-seater; but still there wasn’t enough space for all of them. Ruben and Pete flew overhead, while the others were still congested. Ron’s father drove, Carra’s mother sat in the passenger seat with Tabitha. Behind them, the children were stuffed with the luggage.

They stopped many times to readjust themselves with the luggage, and it took them a little over three hours to reach their destination.

Finally, the car pulled over in front of a big house. An aging man, around 50 years old at guess, opened the front door and rushed out to meet them.

“Ajay!” Ron’s dad called, waving as he pulled out a small suitcase.

“Max!” he shouted back, his Indian accent sounding slightly strange to the friends.

Max quickly introduced all of them to each other.

“Ajay was my colleague before he retired. He is a close friend of mine,” he explained. Turning to his friend, he asked, “Are you sure you don’t mind us staying?”

“No, no, not at all,” he chuckled. “You are all welcome. The animals too, though Kamala will probably want to cover the furniture before they come in.” Grinning broadly, he led them inside.

Chapter 8

“Try this. It is my wife’s specialty,” Ajay invited. It was dinner time, and they were eyeing the table hungrily. Ajay’s servant had taken the animals outside for their dinner. He had bought food for all of them.

The animals had not talked since they entered the house, not wanting to give the old couple a fright.

After they had arrived at the house, Iris had received a vision; the same one as her father had dreamt, though this was unknown to her. She was backed against an invisible wall, and a blur threatened her life. She couldn’t identify it, but she had a doubt that it was the Shadow. She had tried to fight him, but ended up having a decayed hand when she tried to fight off the blur.

Iris had freaked out then, and it took her a long time to recover. She was sure that her family was in trouble, and she almost stormed out of the house to search for the lotus on her own. It took all of them to restrain her. She had calmed down eventually, but the vision still haunted her.

At the moment, she was very grave at the dinner table, refusing to speak to anyone but Ruben. The Indian couple didn’t understand her resolution, but they didn’t press her. Instead, the kind hearted duo tried to distract her by giving delicious dishes for her to try. Slowly, she shook off her misery and enjoyed dinner.

Ajay and his wife gave them three guest rooms. Kamala seemed a little hesitant to let the animals sleep inside, but Ajay persuaded her until she agreed. They ate their dessert- an ice cream which their servant had hurriedly purchased- and were soon snoring in their rooms.

They had woken up early the next morning to find that Kamala had prepared a feast for them to eat then, and also for the journey to Hampi. Ajay even offered them to take his car, seeing that they barely had enough space for everyone.

They agreed, and the two adults sat behind the wheel and they were off.

Ruben suddenly started screeching and clawed at the window next to him. It was mid-day, and they were on a lonely highway.

The others in the same car looked at Ruben in shock. The usually calm hawk was suddenly acting like his life depended on getting out of the car. Iris reached out and slid open the window and her bond flew out in a rush of feathers.

They all peered out the window. Ruben flew up and collided with an incoming bullet speed of black.

“What’s going on?” Carra’s mother, who was driving, halted the car. Behind them, Max’s car also squealed to a stop.

Iris opened the car door and jumped out. The others crowded around her. They squinted upwards, trying to see what was going on against the sun’s bright rays.

Shrill shrieks echoed around as the battle waged on. With a last screech, the black smudge accepted defeat and half flew, half fell to the earth. Ruben followed, clawing the falling bird one last time. Just before it landed, Ruben snatched it in his strong grip and laid it almost gently on the ground. The others all rushed to see.

As they got a better look at what Ruben had attacked, Zevyn gasped. “It’s the same bird which pushed the minivan in Scotland!”

Ruben nodded.

“You just saved our lives!” Tabitha exclaimed.

Iris hugged her bond. “It was probably going to knock us off again.”

May leaned closer to the bird’s face. Slowly, in agony, it opened its eyes.

“Why did you try to attack us again? You promised!” Carra hissed.

“Why didn’t you just give up?” Snowflake snarled.

The bird just groaned and let its head fall.

Lyke gasped. “Is it dead?”

“No,” Ruben growled. “She is a crafty one. She is just trying to trick us. Again.”

“She?”

“The Death Lord sent her. She said he wanted us dead, and that she was the best assassin,” he explained.

“Yeah right. Ruben would have made a better assassin, if he ever had the heart to even take up such an offer,” Josh snorted.

“Should we treat her?” Ron asked cautiously. Pal looked at him exasperatedly.

“Better kill her. But, we aren’t so cruel. Why don’t we just give her to a zoo? After all, where has one seen such a bird?”

The others looked at the limp bird. It was true. She was big, very big, with red eyes. The tips of her tail and wings were white, while her claws were an unexpected pale brown. Her neck had rings of white, and her beak was spotted.

“That’s a good idea. She’d be better off in captivity,” Max agreed. The bird squawked in surprise.

Ruben looked at the others in contempt. The bird realized her mistake and pretended to act dead again.

“So much for playing dead.” Josh sneered. He resisted the urge to kick her, and instead hefted her over his shoulder by a wing. She let out a whimper of pain. Lyke held another wing, while Ron provided support for her scarred claws. Together, the three boys carried the huge bird to one of the cars, where Max immediately tied her up with bits of rope he found.

“Now all we need is a zoo,” he announced.

After about half an hour, they were face to face with a nearby zoo’s veterinarian, who had immediately asked his assistant to take custody of the bird. He had marvelled at the intricate patterns in the rings of white on its neck, but decided to examine it later, once she was treated.

Amy and Max spoke to the vet; they had left the children and the animals in the cars.

They cast one last glance at the bird. She had looked back at them pitifully, but they glared at her coldly. She dropped her head, losing all hope.

They were on the road once more. A few kilometres away from the zoo, they stopped to clean a bloody Ruben up. He stood still as they dabbed paper dripping with water around his neck. He was pretty badly wounded, but he had fared much better than his adversary.

Finally, when they had cleaned him up, they proceeded with their journey. Ruben was still wet, and Tabitha refused to sit next to him no matter what. Pal ended up next to Ruben, and the dog revelled in the hawk’s dampness, enjoying the moisture seeping into his fur.

They stopped for lunch in a highway hotel. The animals were left staring wistfully at their bonds as the children and the adults went inside the restaurant. After they finished their lunch, they bought a parcel meal for their bonds and waited as the animals wolfed down their lunch.

They drove again, halting for a break a couple of hours after lunch to stretch their legs/paws/wings.

They set out again. The children stared at the lonely highway, and a pang of homesickness hit them. Ruben and Pete flew out, relishing the feeling of wind in their feathers. Pal peeped out of the window, panting in the face of the breeze. Tabitha and snowflake curled up together, while the children played games in their separate cars.

It grew darker, and the children got bored of their games. They decided to try to communicate through the cars. But it started raining, and they abandoned that hope. Ruben and Pete rushed back to the cars. The light rain turned into a wild storm, and they were forced to pull over. They parked side by side, and the children told horror tales.

Thunder roared ahead, and only the momentary lightning showed the surroundings. The two adults tried to locate where exactly they were, but there was no signal, and the battery of their torches had died out.

They distributed shawls and jackets to keep warm against the growing chill.

The animals huddled against the children to keep them warm, but it didn’t block out all the cold. The children shivered as they tried to fall asleep.

The thudding of rain on the car roof top kept Pal awake. So he was the only one to realize that there was mist spreading around the cars, and strange lights flickering amidst the fog.

Chapter 10

“What in the world is that?” the children had woken with Pal’s repeated barking, and were astonished to see the mist clouding around them. Strange lights-blue, green and red-were glowing mysteriously in the midst of the fog. Ron’s father had offered to check it out, but none of the others agreed.

“What do we do?” Snowflake asked.

Ron shrugged, shivering. Ruben also offered to check out the lights.

“What if they are not dangerous? I will not take long, I promise. Besides, what is the harm in just looking around quickly? We can go together.” He argued, motioning to Max. The adult had agreed, and grudgingly, Iris allowed her bond to venture outside.

Ruben crept outside, immediately vanishing behind the haze. He flew close to one of the lights, which was flickering eerily. Ron’s father was right next to the hawk, bending down to inspect it.

The light blinked at him, and disappeared, in its place, a little piece of folded up paper. The two looked at each other, and made their way back to the two cars. Once inside, they opened the paper, and found spidery writing all over the page.

Dear Lotus seekers,

I am the guardian of the Lotus. Kindly give up all attempts to gain the Lotus from my grasp, for it will be fruitless. But, however, if you do persist, there may be a certain way to achieve your mission, though it will be dangerous, and I highly recommend you give up now. If you fail that mission, I assure you your journey will end in Heaven (or Hell). But if you finish it, then maybe I can compromise something. But beware; this will be by far the toughest mission you would have ever faced. The mission

“There are some stains after that. I can’t make out anything else.” Max said sadly.

The others looked downcast, none of them making a sound. Pal was the first to break the silence.

“How did that thing, whatever it is, actually find out who we are, and what we are looking for?” he asked, looking frightened and bewildered. The others shrugged.

“What if it’s spying on us?” Pete asked.

“How can it? We’ve never seen it.” Josh said.

Tabitha nodded. “The only one we’ve actually seen is the crow, whatever thing. And she’s been taken care of.”

“Maybe it is hiding in the fog?” Iris suggested.

“But how can it mindread us?” Zevyn argued.

“You have the gift of tongues, don’t you?” Carra asked her suddenly.

“Yes, but I can’t sense stuff,” Zevyn retorted.

“What about you Lyke? Do you have any special powers or anything?” Ron asked hopefully. He shook his head. “Only Zevyn,” he confirmed.

It seemed as if everyone who was present there drooped, all hopes of figuring out what the strange warning meant was burnt.

“Hey!” May said, suddenly shooting straight up. “Hi,” Pal said automatically, but then regretted it as everyone glared at him.

“Well, what is it?” Amy prompted.

“You got that paper when you touched the light, didn’t you?” Max and Ron nodded.

“Maybe, if you get more papers, we can find out what this means!” she said, jiggling around in excitement. The others looked at each other happily.

“Great thinking, May!” Carra’s mother patted her.

“Awesome idea. We’ll go now,” Max announced, looking over at Ruben, who was ruffling up his feathers. The hawk nodded, and the two exited the car in a flash.

They came back soon, each bearing at least two papers each. All had the same spidery handwriting, but a different message.

Dear Lotus Seekers,

It is better if you end this goose chase now. If you don’t, here’s a riddle for you to solve. Decode it, and I will grant you permission to move on.

AN ARROW WILL GUIDE YOU TO A SHRINE

THE SHRINE OF STONE HAS A FERRY FINE

SET SAIL ON IT SLOWLY AND YOU WILL FIND

MAYBE, IT’S NOT JUST A TRICK OF THE MIND.

Have fun with the riddle. But always keep in mind that this hunt is much more dangerous than you think.

The Guardian.

“The rhyme makes no sense!” May protested when they finished reading the first riddle.

Max shrugged. “There’s nothing to do other than follow it.”

“Read the second one,” Snowflake suggested. They turned to the next scroll. The second one didn’t waste ink on greetings. It jumped straight to the point.

So, you’re puzzled by my little rhyme. Read this one, and maybe things will get a little clearer.

STARRY SKIES GRIEVE, LAMENT AND CRY

WHILE YOU ENTER THE LAGOON; GO ON, DON’T BE SHY

DOWN THE STEPS- 273 YOU GO AND STAND BY

REACH A CRANNY, SAY, AND SHOUT HI!

“What? This is more confusing than the last!” Tabitha cried.

“We’d better read all. Then maybe we can get a hang of things.” Amy said, slightly worried.

Well, if you’re still confused, why not give this rhyme a go?

SHOUT IF YOU MUST, TO GET YOUR BEARINGS

BUT SHOUT LOUD, I’M HARD OF HEARING

LOOK TO THE SKY, BUT DON’T TRY STARING,

AN ARROW WILL APPEAR TO SEE HOW YOU’RE FARING!

“Is that the arrow mentioned in the first riddle?” Iris asked. Zevyn nodded. “Could be.”

Ruben handed the last scroll to Ron’s dad.

Try and figure this out. I think you are getting somewhere. But this is a warning, the rhymes as you read were not in order. Please try keep up.

IT’S GETTING WET, AND COLD AND DARK

EVERYTHING SAID SEEMS LIKE AN ECHOING BARK

DON’T BE TERRIFIED, IT’S NOT A SHARK,

BUT BE AFRAID, IT’S NOT AS GENTLE AS A LARK.

“This is getting really confusing,” Pete muttered, resting on Pal. “Maybe, the third one we read is the first,” Pal ventured. Pete shot up straight. “You’re right!” he squawked. “And the first one we read is the second, and then we have to set sail, right? So we’ll end up in water-”

“And then go into a lagoon and everything becomes cold and wet, and there’s something dangerous over there, but not as dangerous as a shark!” Tabitha continued excitedly.

“We have to try that,” Lyke said. The others murmured their agreement.

“But where exactly is that water? And a stone with a ferry? What does that mean?”

“I guess we’re supposed to find a huge stone with a ferry inside it.”

“We’d better just get there; we’ll see what we can do later.”

Chapter 11

“I am so bored,” Ron grumbled.

“But we were just playing!” Iris protested.

The group were still on the journey to Hampi. It was the day after they had found the scrolls. Earlier that morning, they had taken the advice of the rhyme and shouted loudly to the Guardian, then looked at the sky for any sign of the arrow. Finally, after almost half an hour of searching the sky for the arrow, they realized that it wasn’t even an arrow, it was the name of the place they had to get to; it was written ‘Hampi’ clearly, formed by the clouds.

“I’m hungry,” Pal whined. “You always are,” Snowflake sniffed.

“But I am too!” Ron joined in. Max shot his son a glare before handing over a rucksack of food to the boy. Ron’s eyes gleamed as he scouted through the contents of the bag.

They feasted on the sandwiches they had brought. Finally, after another couple of hours of driving, they reached the city of Hampi.

“Now for a hotel,” Amy announced. They drove through the old village, stopping in front of a good-looking hotel. The adults entered, leaving the children and the animals in the cars. Inside, they asked the clerk about the major attractions of Hampi. He handed them a booklet, explaining rapidly.

Thanking him, they exited the hotel with the booklet and climbed into their cars. Once they reached a spot where nobody would see them, they all gathered together.

“The riddle is about a shrine. It’s given in this that the stone chariot here,” Carra’s mother pointed to its picture on the booklet, “was built as a shrine for a god. It’s made of stone, as given, and is the only one which is relatively close to a ferry, because it’s a chariot.”

“That’s awesome!” Josh cried out, his eyes shining.

“We’re nearly there!” Lyke agreed, slapping his sister a hi-five.

“Let’s get this show on the road,” Tabitha mewed, lifting her paws impatiently. They set off, driving to the stone chariot.

When they reached, they jumped out of the cars, vying with each other to be the first to land. Ruben shook his feathers and shot into the sky like a rocket, Pete following more slowly. Pal bounded out excitedly, with Ron chasing him to put on a leash. Iris scooped up Snowflake, before joining the others.

They looked around in awe. The buildings were intricately carved; there were horses, elephants, soldiers, kings, slaves, dancers and many more decorating the walls of the Vittala temple next to the stone chariot. They gazed at the architecture in admiration, forgetting about the rhymes for a moment. They came out of their trance when a dog nearby started howling.

Pal whipped his head around. A young boy was throwing stones at a black and tan dog. Pal growled, but Ron held him back. Before the group could scold the boy, the dog gave a low menacing bark before turning away. A local guide marched up to the boy and dragged him away by the ear. The boy whimpered in pain, but knew better than to scream in public.

“Serves him right.” Pal muttered. Lyke nodded, and they made their way to the stone chariot.

“You know, I think it’s better if we return at midnight. What can we do with everybody here?” Zevyn murmured. Max agreed, and led the group away. They waited in the cars until the moon was up, shining brightly, and stealthily re-entered the temple grounds.

The moon was almost full, casting a bright glow on the chariot. They tip-toed around to the back of the chariot and started inspecting it.

“What are we even supposed to be looking for?” May asked.

“A ferry? Or something like that, I guess,” Zevyn shrugged. Carra’s mother nodded.

“But there is no ferry or a boat on this,” Ruben said, puzzled.

“What if it’s on the inside?” Ron asked.

“Inside?”

“You know, up that ladder thingy out front, inside this temple thing.”

“Worth a try, I suppose.”

Pete flew inside, and searched the interior. The children climbed in, and started searching beside the parrot. Ron tried to go to the back of the shrine, but tripped over Josh who was trying to go out. Ron fell down, and grabbed a piece of rock which was poking out, to save himself from falling inside a hole which somehow just appeared. He screamed. Lyke grabbed his hand and pulled him away.

“Thank you!” he breathed, and screamed again.

“I’ve got to hand it to you, bro, you may be stupid, but you are clever!” Josh said, patting Ron’s back.

“But that doesn’t make sense!” Carra argued.

“I don’t care.” Josh shrugged. They jumped out, and told those waiting outside of the events. Max hugged his son.

“I think we are supposed to go inside that hole. Maybe the ferry is waiting over there.” Iris murmured.

They climbed into the chariot.

“One of us should go there first and check it out,” Pete said.

“I will go,” Ruben volunteered. Before his bond could protest, he added, “If there is danger, I can just fly out. It would be harder for you.”

Reluctantly Iris agreed, and Ruben swooped down silently, clutching a flashlight in his talons.

From above, they could see only the dancing pattern of the flashlight beam. Soon, Ruben appeared at the edge of the opening.

“It is safe,” he reported.

“How far is it?” Zevyn asked.

“There’s a ladder about a metre from the edge. At the bottom, there is a very small strip of land. Do not get down there. When you are on the last rung of the ladder, jump to the left, backwards. It is solid ground there,” he cautioned.

Max went first. Right above, Lyke climbed down, followed by his sister, who was guiding Tabitha down. Ruben led them, offering advice. When Max reached the last rung, the hawk helped him, guiding him with his wing tips. Tabitha, on Zevyn’s back, nimbly jumped down.

Snowflake was right behind the cat, carried by May. Josh and Ron together managed to just keep Pal from falling. The golden retriever got stuck in the middle though, and Ruben, with Lyke’s help, managed to carry the dog to safety. Ron and Josh descended quickly after that. Carra and her mother were last, with Pete bringing the rear. Above them, the hole closed as suddenly as it had opened.

Chapter 16

“Is this stuff edible?” Zevyn frowned at the brown fruit she held in her hands. “It looks like it could kill you,” Josh agreed. Amy shrugged and threw it away. Iris followed her action.

“Mom!” Carra called from further inland. Amy turned her attention on her daughter. Carra was pointing at something in the floor. It was an intricately carved stone slab. A little pushing revealed a key under it.

“Now what the hell is this for?” Josh muttered, picking it up. It was silver, with bits of red and green and blue stones. Tabitha suddenly let out a gasp of surprise. There was a drawing in the stone slab, one which showed the key in a door made of blue gems.

“Now that’s surprising,” Amy commented. Pete sat on the carving, studying it closely. “There’s somebody with an elephant head here. Looks familiar.”

“That’s a Hindu god!” Amy exclaimed, brushing Pete off the slab. He flew off, squawking indignantly. She called Max, who had taken Ron, Pal, Lyke, May and Snowflake to forage for more supplies. He came instantly, the rest of his group crowding behind him.

She showed him the slab and the key. “There are carvings of some Hindu gods too. I studied Indian legends when I was younger. There’s Ganapati, and that one’s Hanuman. That’s Krishna, Vishnu and Shiva. And that one, which is holding the instrument, is Saraswati.” She turned the slab over, which revealed a lot more figures.

“It shows a door. Where could that be?” Ruben asked thoughtfully. “It’s probably in a temple. Some ancient one from around,” Snowflake suggested. “Why?” Pal asked, shaking out his fur for no reason. “There are god’s carvings here.” Snowflake nodded at the stone slab. “I think it’s pretty obvious that gods are found in temples, so probably the door’s there as well.”

“That’s a good observation,” Max noted. May smiled at her bond, and Violet chattered, prancing around like a monkey.

“Where do you think a temple would be over here? And who would have constructed it?” Lyke wondered. “The same people who made the opening in Hampi, and the same people who probably built that ship.”

As Josh said that, everyone remembered those events. It seemed like a lifetime ago to them.

“So now to find this temple and the door, then the lotus and get back to Imagneus,” Iris announced. “What about food?” Ron’s stomach grumbled.

“Fine, food first, temple later.” After finding some edible fruits, they went back to the temple carving, in case they’d missed a clue. They found a small engraving on the other side of the slab. It showed an ‘Om’ symbol next to a huge banyan tree, with a lake on the other side.

“I guess that ‘Om’ represents the temple, and it’s next to a banyan tree, which is next to a lake.” Zevyn squinted at the slab. “Let’s go!”

They set off, Ruben and Pete scouting ahead for any sign of the lake. They soon glided down to join the group. “We can see it up ahead,” Pete reported. “Just follow us.”

Soon, they reached the shore of a big, crystal clear lake, which had an island in the middle. Ruben and Pete flew off to find the banyan tree, while the rest decided to sit down and chat. A swoosh of wings announced the arrival of the two birds.

“The banyan tree and the temple are on the island. We saw both of them,” Pete reported. “How do we cross the lake?” Ron asked, looking at the expanse of water that separated them from the temple. Ruben shook his head. “There does not seem to be any kind of bridge as far as I can see.”

“Can you check again?”

Pete and Ruben rose into the air once more, gliding high above. They landed next to the others after some time.

“There’s a fallen tree,” Pete said. “It looks slippery. You will have to cross carefully.” They followed the two birds to the tree. It was a tall oak tree. The bark was withering, and the water lapped at its bottom. Max decided to go first, and inched along the tree trunk, almost falling over twice. As he neared the end, he grasped the branches for support, and made it across safely. May followed, with Snowflake at her heels. Pretty soon, everyone had made it across, except for Pal, who had fallen over in the middle and was now swimming towards the island.

Before Pal even reached the shore, everybody went to the temple, not wanting to get drenched by one of his fur-shakes. They found the temple pretty quick. It was made of stone and had ivy vines growing along the sides with moss at the base. It had engravings all around which had withered away, but they could make out a very large ‘Om’ symbol at the very front.

The door was a huge slab of stone with a tiny keyhole in the centre. Fishing out the key from his pocket, Max slid it into the hole and turned. A click indicated that the door was unlocked, and it swung open on rusty hinges.

“Do we go inside?” Zevyn asked, glancing eagerly at the cobweb filled doorway of the temple. Max nodded, and led the way inside, grabbing the torchlight from his bag and switching it on. A loud roar stopped them in their tracks.

“Thunder!” Amy called from outside. Ron let out a loud sigh of relief. The patter of rain started, which turned into a storm in no time at all. The sound of the raindrops on the temple walls sounded eerie from inside, seeming to magnify itself when it echoed through the walls.

Iris suddenly stopped, frozen to her spot, staring at a sideway, causing Carra to bump into her. “Hey, what’s wrong? Move-” her words froze on her tongue as she saw what Iris was looking at.

Chapter 18

“Congratulationsss.”

The serpent emerged out of thin air.

“The lotus! This is the one!” Iris exclaimed, her eyes lighting up. The snake’s face contorted into a weird smirk. “You figured it out, I sssssee.”

“Come on! We have to get back now!” Pete called, spreading his wings, ready to take flight.

“Not ssso fassst, birdie,” the snake hissed, amusement in its tone. “What do you mean?” Ron cried.

“You’re the guardian,” Max realized. “The guardian of the lotus.”

“Well done. You realizzzed.”

“Let us go! The Ronens will die if we don’t get there in time!”

“And when, exactly, isss ‘in time’?”

“What the hell? We have to go back now or the Shadow guy will kill everyone!”

“But I never sssaid that I will let you go asss sssoon ass you get the lotusss.”

“You tricked us!”

“Fraud!”

“Me? I never promised anything,” the snake mocked innocently. Iris glared fiercely at the Lotus Guardian.

“Oh, I’ve had enough of this!” Zevyn spat and marched forward, her blade in hand. She catapulted into the air, and, holding her blade forward, drove it into the snake. Or at least, that’s what she expected to happen. Instead, while she was still in the air, the blade disintegrated into sand. Zevyn was so surprised she lost balance but managed to land on her feet in front of the serpent. The other weapons had become miniature sand dunes as well.

“Hey, umm, Lotus?” Ron raised his hand as if to ask a question. The snake turned its piercing eyes on Ron. “Umm, I can call you Lotus, right? ‘Cause Gaurdian of the Lotus is such a long name?” he said, more like a question. The serpent was staring at the boy in shock.

“He’s distracting it! Iris, Lyke, Zevyn, Ruben, you get back to Imagneus as fast as you can. We’ll try to follow. Save the Ronens!” Max whispered urgently. The Lotus Guardian’s gaze was still locked on Ron.

“NO! The Lotus Guardian or Guardian of the Lotus is and always will be my name. You have no right to tamper with such an honourable name,” it hissed angrily.

“Oh! I’m so s-sorry, Lotus Guardian. But d-do you mind if I ask a few questions?” Ron stammered. “Go on,” the snake said with a nod of its head. All the while, Ruben, Iris, Lyke and Zevyn were slowly inching towards the entrance.

“Ummm, so yeah, like, what’s your real name? I mean, you got your name when you were hired right?”

“Hired?”

“Yeah, like when you signed up for this job. You didn’t start guarding the lotus as soon as you were born right?”

“You mean you want my life history?” The snake gazed at Ron with hopeful eyes.

“Umm, yeah, something like that if you don’t mind.”

The snake let out a hiss of delight, and curled up comfortably, wrapping its tail around itself. With its back to the entrance of the room, it didn’t notice the disappearance of two girls, a boy and a hawk.

“Settle down, boy. It’s a long story.”

“And it’s a long night, isn’t it?” Max muttered, standing next to his son.

“Is it night? I thought it was afternoon,” Josh grumbled. They all sat down.

“I was born as the runt of the batch,” the snake started melodramatically. May raised an eyebrow, and Josh rolled his eyes. “My siblings bullied me, and my mother didn’t stop them. I fought back of course, but they were bigger, and they would try and put me in place. My mother abandoned me soon, and left me to survive on my own.” The serpent paused for a breath.

“But I learnt the trickeries of the world and survived on my own. I became stronger everyday and learnt to give what I had to survive. There was this time when a fox tried to eat me. Hah! It got a nasty surprise. It underestimated me, like everyone else.” The Lotus Guardian put on a scowl.

Everyone blocked out the drone of the snake’s voice as it rambled on about its twisted life. After re-accounting about two score incidents, the Guardian finally got to the point where it became the Guardian.

“And the previous Guardian gave me the post with those exact words.” Ron yawned loudly. Josh’s head slumped on Pal, and Carra blinked repeatedly to fight off her drowsiness. The snake hissed at them, irritated.

“Whoa! I’m awake, I’m awake,” Ron held up his hands. Only Josh snored on, undeterred. The Lotus Guardian narrowed its eyes at the sleeping boy.

“Hey, um, Lotus Guardian, I forgot your real name again,” Snowflake said immediately. The snake turned its head. Amy flashed the rabbit a grateful glance before fiercely waking Josh up.

“My name, as I told you three times already, is-”

The serpent was interrupted by Josh’s yawn, which equalled the sound of a flight taking off.

“Enjoyed your dream?” It asked Josh sarcastically. “Oh, yeah.” Josh nodded. “Are you going to let us go now?” Pete asked. The Lotus Guardian glared at him with its fiery gaze.

“No.”